Cid Corman Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Cid Corman Papers.
1954-1989.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Corman, Cid.
.5 linear feet.
Poet, editor and translator, Cid Corman was born in 1924 in Boston, Massachusetts. Owner of the Origin Press, he was the editor and publisher of Origin magazine.
MSS19970103
Biography
Poet, editor and translator, Cid Corman was born in 1924 in Boston, Massachusetts. Owner of the Origin Press, he was the editor and publisher of Origin magazine.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence, with some poetry manuscripts interfiled with the correspondence. Significant correspondents include Donald Allen, Nicholas Dean, Vincent Ferrini, Stephen Jonas, LeRoi Jones, Jeremy Prynne, and letters to David Giannini, Louis Rowan and Benice Weiss.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary materials and the records of several small presses. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Bibliography
About the Author:
Ann Charters. “Cid Corman, “ American Poets Since World War II, ed. Donald J. Greiner Dictionary of Literary Biography ,vol. 5.Detroit: Gale Research, 1980.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Allen, Donald Merriam, 1912- —Correspondence.; Dean, Nicholas—Correspondence.; Ferrini, Vincent, 1913- —Correspondence.; Giannini, David—Correspondence.; Jonas, Stephen—Correspondence.; Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934- —Correspondence.; Prynne, J.H., 1936- —Correspondence.; Rowan, Louis—Correspondence.; Weiss, Bernice—Correspondence.
Subjects:
Origin Press.; Origin.; Poets, American—20th century.; American poetry—20th century.; American poetry—Periodicals.; Poetry—Editing.; Authors and publishers—United States.; Publishers and publishing—United States.; Periodicals—Publishing—Massachusetts.; Massachusetts—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Boston (Mass.)—Cultural Affairs—Literature.; Massachusetts—Newspapers, periodicals, and journalism.; Boston (Mass.)—Newspapers, periodicals, and journalism.; Poems.
Document Types:
Correspondence.
Occupations:
Poet.; Editor.; Publisher.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased from Mr. Corman by the University of Connecticut.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Incoming Correspondence, 1954-1980
  - Allen, Donald, 1964 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Allen, Donald, 1964 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Dean, Nicholas, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Donahue, Wade, ca. 1954 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Ferrini, Margaret, 1961-1973 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Ferrini, Vincent, 1960-1969 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Ferrini, Vincent, 1971-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Jonas, Stephen, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Jonas, Stephen, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Jonas, Stephen, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Jonas, Stephen, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Jonas, Stephen, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Jonas, Stephen, 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Jonas, Stephen, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Jones, LeRoi, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Kessler, Jascha, 1954 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Prynne, Jeremy H., 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Prynne, Jeremy H., 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Prynne, Jeremy H., 1961 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Sorrentino, Gilbert, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Wieners, John, 1957 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Wieners, John, 1957 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
- Series II: Outgoing Correspondence, 1966-1989
  - Giannini, David, 1980 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Giannini, David, 1983-1984 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Giannini, David, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Giannini, David, 1986-1987 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Giannini, David, 1988-1989 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 33)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 34)
  - Rowan, Louis, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 35)
  - Weiss, Bernice, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 36)